while coal plunging has gained a lot of
popularity recently people have been
using the benefits of cold plunging for
hundreds of years possibly even
thousands these benefits include
speeding up muscle recovery possibly
boosting your immune system and even
offering mental clarity polar monkeys
sent us two of their models of cold
plunges so today i'm gonna plunge into
all the details about these icy plunges
let's get right to it
[Music]
what's up everybody it's jake back at
the barbing garage gym and for today's
video i have two cold plungers from
polar monkeys in this review i'm going
to take you through all the details
about these cold plunges from the price
the features the pros and the cons as
well as who should or maybe should not
buy one of these but before i get going
we've reviewed a lot of cold plunges on
barbin.com so if you want to browse our
best list just go ahead and search
barbend best cold plunges and you can
find out for yourself which ones we like
the best okay so once again i have two
different models of their cold plunges
the portal which is behind me and the
fiberglass brain pod which i'm sitting
on right now so the portal and the
portal le which stands for limited
edition because it has a graphic on it
those are gonna vary in how you want
them to look which is pretty cool in my
opinion so ours is black but you can
also get it in regular steel
all their models are two feet wide or so
and right around two feet tall but with
the portal and the portal le you can
either have them be four feet long or
six feet long
that's gonna be really nice for anybody
who's well over six feet tall you're
probably going to be interested in one
of those bigger models
my favorite though has to be this
brainpod it's made from fiberglass so
it's going to be more comfortable in my
opinion to sit in instead of that steel
tub but it also has a limited edition
monkey graphic on the side which i just
think it looks really cool that makes it
look pretty unique in my opinion
i would be doing you all a major
disservice if i did not mention that
these are more affordable affordable
than some competition out there i'm not
talking about saving a couple hundred
bucks i'm talking about saving thousands
of dollars compared to that competition
minus their star treatment model which
is their most luxurious one don't worry
i'll dig into the price in just a minute
now the chiller on the side is gonna get
your water down to 36 degrees without
needing any ice whatsoever but it's also
going to double and turn this plunge
into a hot tub with temperatures
reaching up to 103 degrees without
having to pay anything extra like some
other companies are going to have to
make you do the filter and the ozone
generator are gonna keep your water
clean from you know any bacteria but you
should still probably drain your water
every now and again and that's pretty
easily done because the drain does have
a hose hookup that way you can direct
all your water away from your electrical
outlet as well as your electrical
components and just for your own safety
that's a nice little touch right there
and lastly it's super easy to set up
once you have your pump chiller filter
all connected and it's plugged in
just simply toss in your hose let it
fill up with water from there all you
have to do is set the temperature where
you want it and it's just smooth sailing
after that
[Music]
okay so i know i just said a lot of
great things about these cold plunges
but there's still a few things that some
people might not be too crazy about
let's talk about the money first i know
i just got done saying you could be
saving a couple thousand dollars if you
were to go with one of these models
compared to some other companies and
that's still true but it's still a
luxury item and you still need to be
prepared to spend around 2 grand even on
their cheapest model
if that's something you just don't want
to do or maybe you don't think you're
not gonna use it enough for that price
tag you could always toss in some water
and ice into your bathtub at home or
maybe even a trash can you know
preferably a clean one but i'm not gonna
tell you what to do with your life you
also don't have any accessories that are
thrown in with the original purchase and
that's including the insulated cover
don't worry i'll dig into what all those
accessories are in a minute and how much
they cost but just know that it is going
to increase that original price tag the
wood and fiberglass models are pretty
durable but it's probably not going to
be as durable as an acrylic tub would be
and they're not really that big but
you're still going to need at least
around 10 square feet of space which
could definitely be a problem for some
people
okay so if you head over to the polar
monkeys website you'll find all the
models that they have available for
purchase the brainpod is listed right
around 3 500 bucks i know that's still a
pretty good chunk of change but you know
once again this does double as a hot tub
you don't have to pay extra for that you
know some other companies are gonna make
you pay extra for that feature and you
know some of them even charge nearly
five grand for a tub that only features
cold water so it's a pretty big bargain
in my opinion the portal and the portal
le once again there's some variety in
terms of your size that's gonna change
the price and with the regular version
of the portal like we have you have two
different options either regular steel
or black like we have behind me right
here
now the four foot long regular steel
build that's gonna be right around 2 200
bucks while the six foot long regular
steel version that's gonna be around
2700 bucks the four foot long black one
is gonna cost you about twenty four
hundred dollars a six foot long black
portal that's going to be around 2 900
bucks portal le only comes in black with
the monkey graphic on the side which is
pretty sweet once again so that four
foot long model it's gonna be around 2
800 bucks on the six foot one that's
gonna be around thirty two hundred
dollars the star treatment model is
their most luxurious model they have and
you're also gonna have to pay for that
it's gonna be right around eight grand
that's a pretty good chunk of change as
well but you know the pump filter
chiller everything's within the actual
framework of the tub so you don't have
to see it's probably going to be easier
to assemble it and you can even control
your temperature settings from your
phone so that more luxurious experience
like i said might be worth the price tag
okay so let's talk about the build now
with these plunges that's gonna change
depending on which one you decide to go
with so let's talk about the brainpod
first once again it is made from
fiberglass it's right around five and a
half feet long just you know maybe a
shade under two feet tall and with your
plumbing your chiller and everything
it's a little over four feet wide it
weighs 140 pounds when it's empty and
right around 600 pounds when it's full
now remember the portal and the portal
le are available in both four feet and
six feet long they're gonna be right
around two feet tall as well and with
you know your plumbing and everything a
shade over four feet so the four foot
long tubs weigh right around 100 pounds
and they're empty and around 800 pounds
when they're full while the six foot
long tubs weigh 120 pounds and they're
empty and about a thousand pounds when
they're full the star treatment model
once again it's made from wood
all your plumbing and everything is
within the actual tub itself so it's
seven feet long two feet tall and two
feet wide
and it's gonna weigh around 340 pounds
when it's empty and i don't know how
much it weighs exactly when it's full
but i think it's pretty safe to assume
it's going to be well over a thousand
pounds now the cool thing about the
chiller is that you don't have to pay
anything extra to get your water to cool
off or get hotter at a faster rate it's
all the exact same regardless of which
model that you decide to go with
now these aren't small they're not
necessarily huge but you could still run
into a spacing issue because you're
going to need around 10 square feet of
space so just keep that in mind you know
if you don't have that available space
you can find some companies that feature
a plunge that resembles a barrel
but in my personal opinion i think you
can run into the issue of some heat
pockets being formed in your legs from
them not being fully extended
and that's something you don't have to
worry about with any of these tubs
so let's talk about those accessories
that i mentioned earlier remember none
of these come with your original
purchase so you're going to have to add
these on when you're going to check out
so this is going to include the
insulated cover a gfci extension cord as
well as a smart plug now if you don't
know what a gfci extension is
essentially your plunge is going to be
plugged into that cord and then that
core is going to get plugged into your
outlet this is going to you know prevent
any electrical shock maybe even some
fire so for your own safety i definitely
just snagged that it's only about 35
bucks it's worth getting if you plan on
plunging outside you know i highly doubt
you want some bugs and grass and
everything getting into your tub so
you're gonna want this insulated cover
it's right around 450 bucks it's also
going to help you keep your temperature
you know locked in
the ozone generator that's going to be
kind of essential in my opinion as well
because it's going to help you keep your
water clean that's right around 400. you
might just want to go ahead and get that
as well really the only thing that i
would consider maybe not necessary is
the smart plug so what this does it
allows you to you know pair it up with
your phone you got to download the casa
app this is going to allow you to set a
timer or schedule to turn your plunge on
and off every day but you can't control
the temperature settings so once again
that's probably why i wouldn't consider
it necessary it's going to be around 55
bucks now if you ever need to purchase
any new parts for your existing plunge
you can definitely do so so there's a
hose that connects the pump to the
chiller it's going to be around 50 bucks
a new chiller itself is around 2 grand
and a new pump is going to be around 100
or so and instead of a light being built
into the actual plunge itself polar
monkeys is going to toss in a
submersible light which is actually
pretty cool in my opinion you just
untwist it there's three aaa batteries
that go in here and it comes with a
remote that way you can completely
customize which color you want kind of
add some ambiance to your plunging
experience and you don't receive any
type of water treatment package there's
nothing to purchase on their website so
if you want any chlorine or anything to
really keep that water crystal clear you
have to go add that on for yourself and
it doesn't come with a skimmer net to
get any lingering debris out so i went
and got this one from walmart it's only
a couple bucks i'd suggest you doing the
same it gets the job done pretty well in
my opinion
all right guys let's do a quick walk
around with both of these cold plungers
i'm going to start with the brain pod as
you can see we do have that limited
edition monkey graphic on the front that
i've been talking about it's also going
to be featured on the portal le it's
just really cool in my opinion it's
pretty unique and i haven't seen any
other cold plunges like that once again
the brain pod is made from fiberglass
nice and comfortable to sit in it's more
comfortable than the portal in my
opinion don't worry i'll dig into those
details in a second obviously i have my
toys right here makes it a little bit
more fun and enjoyable but i'm going to
talk about this light right here this is
a submersible light you do have a remote
that comes with it simply cut it on and
you have a lot of color options for you
to work with here so you know you can
pick whatever color you want and just
simply
set that down into your plunge and it's
going to light up the water at night
it's pretty cool now you also have your
drain as well as a jet on the side of
the plunge right here that jet's going
to circulate the water and keep it from
becoming stagnant which you definitely
don't want to happen so let's come
around back now and this is where all
your hardware is going to be let's start
with the chiller thing takes up a good
amount of space but it's awesome like i
said it goes down to 36 degrees goes up
to 103 degrees it's really easy to use
all you have to do is press the set
button select your desired temperature
and then that's it's going to take care
of everything else on its own which is
pretty awesome now this box right here
you might wonder what that is well don't
worry i'm going to tell you
all of your cords are going to want to
go in here it's where you're going to
want everything to be
this way you don't have to worry about
anything becoming damaged from any type
of water at all it's going to stay nice
and dry so where your ozone generator
it's where you're going to want to put
it just for your own safety in the
beginning all your cords are going to go
in this black box right here and that's
going to help but i would definitely
just recommend using this box even if
you don't purchase the ozone generator
just you know for safe keeping keep
everything nice and dry pretty simple
toss that back on
clamp all these down
and you're good to go now
your filter is right here
as well as your pump and you can see
that hose connects the pump to the
chiller but over here you do have that
drain if you want to drain your water
it's really easy to do there's a little
knob you just twist it water is going to
flow out but you can connect your hose
and it's going to make that even better
all that water is going to get directed
completely away from everything here
which is really nice you have to worry
about any of this getting wet which is
pretty cool now let's transition this
portal right here we have the six foot
long portal once again it does come in
four feet
i gotta say in my time with both of
these models right here
this definitely felt colder when i was
in it they're both 36 degrees but
you know sitting on this steel just felt
colder overall in my opinion it's also
half a foot longer and it does seem to
be a little bit taller so you're going
to be sitting deeper in that water i'm
not going to bring you around back
because basically everything is the
exact same but i just wanted to
highlight it a little bit
and remember we have the black one also
comes in regular steel and that portal
le would have that monkey graphic right
here on the front
[Music]
okay so who should purchase a cold
plunge from polar monkeys well if you're
looking for a designated cold plunge
that can actually double as a hot tub i
think you'll be really happy that you
can't go wrong with any of these models
because you do get that hot water and
you're going to be paying you know a
discounted price compared to some other
competition
because of the filter and the ozone
generator your water is going to stay
relatively clean which is really nice
you still might want to throw in some
chlorine to help you out but you know
it's nice knowing that those things are
going to help keep your water clean and
especially with the insulated cover it's
going to keep out debris grass bugs
whatever it may be but also you know
keeping that temperature locked into
place and helping out that chiller a
little bit which is also going to be
what's really driving that temperature
so that's really nice no more bags of
ice i think you all are going to really
enjoy that and if you want to plunge
when it's dark outside you definitely
can submersible light is really cool in
my opinion at a little color options you
can work with and it's just going to add
to that ambiance
[Music]
okay now what about the people who might
not want to purchase one of these cold
plunges well really there's just a
couple things you got to think about
let's talk about the money yeah i've
said it a couple times you're going to
be saving money compared to some
competitors
but you still have to be prepared to
spend at least two thousand dollars
that's something you just simply don't
wanna do you know you could absolutely
still use your bathtub fill it up with
some water and ice or maybe even a trash
can but like i said earlier use a clean
one
and the dimensions you know they're not
too bad but you still need at least
around 10 square feet of space and if
you don't have that much available space
well then it's just simply not going to
work out for you and also you know if
you're really particular about your
materials you might not be too thrilled
that none of these models are available
in acrylic which could technically last
you longer than any of the ones that are
available well that's about all i have
for y'all today on the polar monkeys
cold plunge you know once again we do
have the portal and brain pod models you
can't really go wrong with any of the
models that they have because they do
feature the exact same pump filter and
chiller and they're going to feature the
same exact temperature range from 36
degrees up to 103 degrees
and you're gonna be saving some money
even though you have to add on the
accessories compared to some other
competition minus that star treatment
model which once again is more luxurious
it's made from wood and you know all the
hardware is hidden out of sight which is
pretty nice
thanks for watching y'all i hope this
video was really helpful and that i was
able to answer some questions about
polar monkeys and the cold plunges that
they have available stay tuned for my
next review but for now head over to
barbin.com and you can read more about
these two specific models and the other
ones that i've mentioned just search bar
bend polar monkeys cold plunge review
and all the details will be there for
you i'll see y'all next time
[Music]
you